Gabriel Diegel

Email: gabriel.diegel@icloud.com Github: https://github.com/gdiegel

Executive Summary

Creative Software Engineer with 15 years of demonstrated experience in Software Engineering, Solutions Architecture, and Technology Leadership. Deep expertise in Distributed Systems, Microservices, Event-Driven Architecture, and Continuous Delivery. Highly motivated self-starter with a winning mindset and a bias for action.

Currently

Senior Software Engineer at LeagueApps in New York, US

Programming languages

Java, Go, Kotlin, Python

Technologies

Spring Boot, WebFlux, Quarkus, Echo, Docker, Kubernetes, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Pub/Sub, Maven, Gradle, Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Terraform, Datadog

Experience

2023-current

Senior Software Engineer at LeagueApps in New York, US

- Lead architectural modernization efforts with new microservice-based backend
- Lead development of next-generation schedule import solution
- Designed and implemented event-driven state synchronization system
- Solved performance issues, making legacy endpoints up to 90% faster

2019-2022

Senior Software Engineer at Tekton in Lima, Peru

- Developed microservice-based backend for US fintech
- Implemented event-driven architecture

2018-2019

Senior Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany

- Developed modular test strategy, tooling, and reporting for web-based frontend tests
- Developed and supported strategy and framework for integrating functional acceptance tests into company-wide continuous delivery framework
- Planned, executed and analyzed performance tests for next-generation backend store architecture and Single-Sign-On solution, implemented metrics and data gathering in InfluxDB, analyzed and visualized data in Grafana
- Supervised theses of graduate students
- Lead test automation guild

2013-2018

Software Development Engineer in Test at 1&1 Internet SE in Karlsruhe, Germany

- Developed acceptance test suites in Java for a broad range of backend services using protocols like HTTP,
 SMTP, IMAP, and POP3
- Developed declarative framework in Java for HTTP-based API tests
- Developed RESTful web service with Spring Boot for collecting metrics of deployed software artifacts

2010-2012

Analyst at Atos Worldline GmbH in Frankfurt, Germany

- Analyzed data reports drawn from large-scale customer data and transaction database
- Developed a CLI tool in Python for data management, extracting data from mainframe database, filtering, and automatically loading into Oracle databases

2009-2010

2009

Software Engineer at Fraunhofer Institute for Physical Measurement Techniques IPM in Freiburg, Germany

- Developed software for an automated particle detection system
- Integrated a fast hardware-based data acquisition system

Education

B.Sc. in Psychology at Universität Hagen, Germany

Dipl.-Ing. (FH) in Electrical Engineering at Hochschule Karlsruhe, Germany

Thesis: "Development of an automated image analysis software for a fluorescence-based data acquisition system for the detection of airborne microorganisms"

Projects

2016 retryJ: A re

retryJ: A retry library for Java

Languages

German: Native English: Fluent Spanish: Fluent Italian: Learning

Articles

"Take your testing DSL to the next level with custom assertions"
"JUnit5—Feeble screams from forests well known"
"Using neo-problem with a pure Spring Boot service"
"Writing a custom test engine with Kotlin"

2019 "Automated acceptance testing"

2019 "Running acceptance tests on GitlabCI"